<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My Take on the World]]></title>
  <link href="http://frakentoaster.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://frakentoaster.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-21T01:17:31-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://frakentoaster.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rick Houser]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leave Your Mark on Mars (via NASA)]]></title>
    <link href="http://frakentoaster.github.io/blog/2015/08/20/leave-your-mark-on-mars/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-20T21:53:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://frakentoaster.github.io/blog/2015/08/20/leave-your-mark-on-mars</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
	NASA announced it will be accepting names to board the InSight spacecraft on its upcoming mission to Mars.
</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>
	In 1977 NASA sent its first time capsule of sorts into deep space.
	Aboard Voyager 1 and Voyager 2 are <a href="http://voyager.jpl.nasa.gov/spacecraft/goldenrec.html">discs made of gold</a> that hold images and sounds from Earth. While Voyager 2 is now in the outermost layer of the heliosphere, Voyager 1 has left our solar system and is now in interstellar space.
</p>
<p>
	If you missed the opportunity back in '77 or if you weren't around at the time like myself, now is your chance to leave your mark in space all without taking a day off work.
</p>
<p>
	NASA will be sending a silicon microchip containing the names of those wanting to take part. In March of 2016, the spacecraft InSight will launch from California carrying the names. Insight will make its 6 month long journey to Mars, landing at a point fittingly called "Elysium Planitia, (Plain of Ideal Happiness)". To get an idea of just how far this is, check out how these Web Developers represent this journey<a href="http://www.distancetomars.com/"> in pixels! =)</a>.
</p>
<p>
	I'm so stoked today because I get to be part of Mars' history.
	If you'd like to learn more or you want to be my Martian neighbor, you can do so by clicking <a href="http://mars.nasa.gov/participate/send-your-name/orion-first-flight/">here!</a>
</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google vs the Human Condition]]></title>
    <link href="http://frakentoaster.github.io/blog/2015/08/19/google-vs-the-human-condition/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-19T13:00:09-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://frakentoaster.github.io/blog/2015/08/19/google-vs-the-human-condition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>	
	Google's co-founder Larry Page recently announced the reorganizing of Google as Alphabet, and it's mission to fight some of mankind's most basic ailments.
</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>
	We all know Google, as the billionaire tech giant who dominates internet searches. What many may not realize is they are much much more.
	From their own programming language Go to self-driving cars, Google seems to dominate technology. The industry goliath, with all their brilliant scientists and engineers now turn their focus on the prevention of disease.
</p>
<p>
	While that may come as a surprise to some, this has really been a long time coming. Ever hear of Google X?
	Google X is a facility of research that encompasses Artificial Intelligence, Computational neuroscience, Health care and Biotechnology and was founded back in 2010.
	The Life Sciences division at Google X has been researching medicine for some time now. Under Alphabet, problems with human affliction will no longer just be a side project. It will be their guiding mission.
</p>
<p>
	Google has many divisions and projects going on. Too many to be covered with one blog post.
	To learn more about Google's fantastic "moonshots" and how you can play a part in the future, check out some of their <a href="https://www.solveforx.com/search/moonshots">projects here.</a> 
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
